Dive deep into serious learning,
and get excited!
Witness a miracle born from fossils.
Once upon a time, in a certain place...
Prehistoric creatures full of personality!
Tirano, Stego, Ammonite,Trilobite.
They've been saying "hi" for 500 million years.
Prehistory! Everybody Say (Roar!)
Ancient, Alright! Future, FLY High!
A herd of mammoths! Run!
Thud thud thud thud! On your marks, get set, go!
Dive deep into serious learning,
and get excited!
Witness a miracle born from fossils.
Dive deep into serious learning,
Playing for real.
The universe begins with passion.
Super happy!
Serious Dunkleosteus Comedy Contest
Kanna-san,
let me walk you to the clubroom!
I told you I'm not going!
Zebras and lions live in herds, you know!
I am neither a zebra nor a lion!
BEHOLD!
The excavated skull of Dunkleosteus!
W-What's up with you all of a sudden?!
It's just the head, but its body must have been huge too.
but its body must have been huge too.
That's it!
Dunkleosteus was the top marine predator of the Late Devonian period,
but only head bones have been found,
so its exact body shape and size remain unknown!
And so, today's topic is...
THE WORLD OF SERIOUS PALEONTOLOGY!
Again?
Whoa!
The ocean?!
Oh no!
We're drowning!
This is the sea of the Devonian period!
Wow, amazing!
How are you two talking normally under water?!
Now then,
draw what you think Dunkleosteus's body looked like on this skull
Why did this turn into a comedy drawing segment?!
Done!
That was fast!
Let's see, Dino-kun...
It looks like a Great White Shark!
Splendid!
Around 2017,
Dunkleosteus was hypothesized to resemble sharks!
Its bite force was twice that of a Great White!
The part that looks like teeth is actually modified bone used to slice meat!
Hey, that's way too much info!
How did you cram all that in your drawing?!
Since that was a great answer,
here's a trilobite fossil for you, Dino-kun!
Thank you very much!
Alright,
next is Kanna-kun,
go ahead!
EH? Me?
Go on,
Kanna-san!
Don't look at me like that...
I'll just draw something random.
Here,
take this!
Kanna-kun, that is...
I kind of made a joke out of it...
MARVELOUS!
Did you already know that Dunkleosteus had a head
and shoulder area heavily covered in dense armor plate?
So,
Kanna-san drew the skull shaped like suit of armor based on that fact?!
Indeed!
as expected of Kanna-kun!
No, no, no! There's no deep meaning behind it at all!
Sensational answers from both of you!
I'm telling you, it was a total coincidence!
President Tetori, please tell us the actual answer!
Very well!
Here is the actual answer!
In the past, based on head size, it was estimated to be 10 meters long.
Recent studies suggest an average length of around 3.5 meters!
Its jaw force was extraordinarily powerful,
crushing prey like Coelacanths.
Furthermore, it could open its mouth
in 0.02 seconds and close it in 0.06 seconds!
With such bite force and high-speed jaw opening,
Dunkleosteus reigned supreme as the apex predator of ancient oceans!
Well, pretty amazing, right?
If there's a current consensus theory,
why didn't you just tell us that from the beginning?!
It's the mainstream theory,
but nothing is set in stone!
If new fossils are discovered,
its shape could change again.
That's the beauty and romance of paleontology!
I see!
So President wanted to teach us that...
How ridiculous.
I'm going home!
Wait a moment!
What?
WHAT IS IT?
Since Kanna-kun's answer was so marvelous,
here is the trilobite fossil I forgot to hand over!
Please accept it!
That's amazing, Kanna-san!
I don't want it.